National Negro Opera Company Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Administrative Papers, 1912-1961, bulk 1931-1960, (73 folders) (Box 20-24, 67)
  Records of the National Negro Opera Company's business activities. Included among these materials are charters, by-laws, contracts, lists of officers and board members, planning information, and meeting minutes. Includes records from the National Negro Opera Foundation, early records from the National Association of Negro Musicians (Pittsburgh branch), and other related organizations and committees. Minutes of meetings from these organizations are arranged in chronological order. Diplomas and other early public school and college certificates belonging to Mary Cardwell Dawson are also included in this series and are found in the Miscellany subseries.
  Arranged by type of material. Minutes are further arranged chronologically.
  - Advertising, 1957, undated (Box-folder 24/1)
  - Appointment Books, 1943-1948 (Box 22)
    - Appointment book, 1943, Material laid in. (Box-folder 22/1)
    - Appointment book, 1944 (Box-folder 22/2)
    - Appointment book, 1945 (Box-folder 22/3)
    - Appointment book (Week-at-a-glance), 1948 (Box-folder 22/4)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1944-1958 (Box-folder 24/9)
  - Business Cards, undated (Box-folder 24/2)
  - Calendars, 1938-1959 (Box 22)
    - Calendar, 1938, Material laid in. (Box-folder 22/5)
    - Calendar #1, 1943, Material laid in. (Box-folder 22/6)
    - Calendar #2, 1943, Material laid in. (Box-folder 22/7)
    - Calendar, 1945 (Box-folder 22/8)
    - Calendar, 1950 (Box-folder 22/9)
    - Calendar, January-June 1959 (Box-folder 22/10)
    - Calendar, July-December 1959 (Box-folder 22/11)
  - Certificates, 1953 (Box 24)
    - Certificates of Merit (NNOC), July 25, 1953 (Box-folder 24/3)
  - Contracts, 1937-1961 (Box 21)
    - Adams, Pearl, February 18, 1956 (Box-folder 21/1)
    - Allen, William, May 11, 1937 (Box-folder 21/1)
    - American Guild of Musical Artists, Inc., April 28, 1954 (Box-folder 21/1)
    - American Guild of Musical Artists, Inc., February 24, 1956 (Box-folder 21/1)
    - American Guild of Musical Artists, Inc. [not signed], 1958 (Box-folder 21/1)
    - Ball, Robert P. (Pete Ball's Auto Clinic), March 1958 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Baynton's, March 1958 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Bergmann's, Inc., November 1960 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Brooks & Allen, November 17, 1960 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Brown, Debra, December 4, 1959, Two signed copies. (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Brown, Debra, December 14, 1959, Two signed copies. (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Browne, Delores, September 24, 1954 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Bruce, Sadie, March 11, 1952 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Burton, Perola, March 1952 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Chandler, William, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Chandler, William (William Chandler Company, Inc.), November 1960 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Chesapeake Heights on the Bay, November 17, 1960 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Clarke, Lucienne M. (Lucienne Clarke Dance Studio), January 22, 1960, Two signed copies. (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Cloonan, Gilbert C. (Superintendent, Allegheny County Soldiers and Sailors Memorial Hall, Piitsburgh, PA), February 24, 1954 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Colemon, Annie Mae, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Coles, Rybye M., August 30, 1957, Two unsigned copies. (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Collins, LeRoy, February 29, 1944 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Collins, LeRoy, March 1, 1944 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Cook, Destalear, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Cornell 3-Hour Cleaners, May 1958 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Coberson, George W. (Principal, A. Leo Weil High School, Pittsburgh), March 19, 1943 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Davis, R. W. (R. W. Davis, Painter-Plasterer), May 1958 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Deere, James D., November 14, 1959 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Democratic Club of Red Bank [New Jersey], March 1958 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Dines, Charles, December 14, 1959 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Dixon, Angela G., March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Eckles, John, December 14, 1959 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Federated Republican Club of Red Bank, New Jersey, March 1958 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Felder, Robert N. (Bobby), October 3, 1960 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Feldman, Samuel, March 22, 1949 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Forman, Margaret, April 11, 1955 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Frazier, Mrs. A. S., March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Friend, John Edward, September 7, 1956 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Gatto, Angelo, September 15, 1954 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Gertrude's Beauty Shop, March 1958 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Gillis, Henrine K., December 14, 1959 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Grant, Albert J., December 14, 1959 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Greene, Evelyn, December 14, 1959 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Greene, Evelyn, September 20, 1960 see also Correspondence: Greene, Evelyn see also Photographs: Greene, Evelyn (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Greenidge, Lisle, April 1949 see also Correspondence: Greenidge, Lisle see also Photographs: Greenidge, Lisle (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Groomes, Jeanette, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Gwin, Huel Brooks, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Gwin, Huel Brooks, March 29, 1952 see also Correspondence: Gwin, Huel Brooks see also Photographs: Gwin, Huel Brooks (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Hallman, Elizabeth, December 14, 1959 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Harris, Alfonzo B., January 27, 1949 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Harris, Carrie A., March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Harvey, Julia S., March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Henderson, Pearl, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Hoskins, John, January 1948 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Hunt, John, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Hylton, Taft, December 14, 1959 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Industrial Bank of Washington, D.C., November 1960 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Jackson, Lillian, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Jacobs Hardware Company (Red Bank, New Jersey), March 1958 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Jenkins, Delores B., March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Johnson, Juanita, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Johnson, Magga Worthington, March 1, 1952 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Johnson, Magga Worthington, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Jones, Harold E., March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Jones, Virginia B., December 14, 1959 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Jones, William, December 16, 1950, Contract for the presentation of The Ordering of Moses at Cumberland, Maryland. (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Kiser, Ruth D., March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Keyes, Pansy, December 14, 1959 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - King, Omega, March 1, 1952 see also Correspondence: King, Omega see also Photographs: King, Omega (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Lawes Coal Company (Red Bank, New Jersey), March 1958 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Lee, Percy, March 1958 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Logan, Albert N., March 1, 1952 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Logan, Albert N., March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Lucas, James, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Major, Thomas, 1951 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - McClam, Hortence A., March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - McFerrin, Robert, March 28, 1949 see also Correspondence: McFerrin, Robert see also Photographs: McFerrin, Robert (Box-folder 21/5)
    - McGowan, Mayoma, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Meistrich Agency (Red Bank, New Jersey), March 1958 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Miller, T. H., January 4, 1944 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Nash, Joseph, September 24, 1954 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Nauman, Henri, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Nobile, Anthony, September 1944 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Oliver, Reene Vay, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - O'Loughlin, Roy, December 14, 1959 see also Correspondence: O'Loughlin, Roy see also Music: Dett, R. Nathaniel. The Ordering of Moses. O hear me Lord. Additional aria and letter by Roy O'Loughlin (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Page, Marian, December 14, 1959 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Peterson, Caleb, March 24, 1955 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Poyas, Dorothy, December 14, 1959 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Price, Robert, Jr., March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Price, Sam, March 3, 1957 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Rahn, Muriel, April 1949 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Rahn, Muriel, July 15, 1954 see also Correspondence: Rahn, Muriel see also Photographs: Rahn, Muriel (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Rainbow, John, December 14, 1959 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Reed, Napoleon, April 1949 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Reed, Napoleon, July 2, 1954, Three unsigned copies. (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Reed, Napoleon, August 17, 1954 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Rich, Charles, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Salna, Valdena, March 1, 1952 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Shoppe, Ruth Ann, March 1954 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Silver Licquors (New Shrewsbury, New Jersey), March 1958 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Sissle, Noble, May 26, 1955 see also Correspondence: Sissle, Noble see also Photographs: Sissle, Noble (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Smith, Jackson, March 28, 1949 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Stewart, Shirley W., March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Stone, Theodore Charles, September 1954 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Tanner, Amanda, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Thomas, Kathleen, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Thompson, Dolph (Associated Counselors International), January 6, 1960 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Turner, Mrs. Eddis, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Turner, Leola, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Tessmer, Joseph M., June 30, 1961 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Vallee, Carlos C., circa 1944 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Vincent, Fritz, May 22, 1956 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Virginia Club of the Convent Avenue Baptist Church, New York, January 3, 1958 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Voorhees, Bettye, April 1949 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Voorhees, Bettye, December 14, 1959 see also Correspondence: Voorhees, Bettye see also Photographs: Voorhees, Bettye (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Weston, Inez, March 18, 1952 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Whaley, Lawrence L., November 1960 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Whelan's Corset Shop (Washington, D.C.), November 1960 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Wilson, Horace, December 14, 1959 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Zane, William, March 1, 1952 (Box-folder 21/7)
  - Contracts (Multiple Contractees), April 20, 1944, Signed by 43 performers. (Box-folder 21/8)
  - Contracts (Multiple Contractees - Chorus), May 25, 1956 (Box-folder 21/8)
  - Contracts (Multiple Contractees - Dancers), May 27, 1956 (Box-folder 21/8)
  - Contracts (Unused Performer forms), 1940s-1960 (Box-folder 21/9)
  - Contracts (Unused Advertisers forms), 1940s-1961 (Box-folder 21/10)
  - Contracts (Costume Responsibility Agreements - The Ordering of Moses Performance), June 13, 1951 (Box-folder 21/11)
  - Contracts (Costume Responsibility Agreements - The Ordering of Moses Notebook), January 1957 (Box-folder 21/12)
  - Contracts (Miscellaneous), undated (Box-folder 21/13)
  - Corporate Papers, 1950-1960, undated (Box 20)
    - Certificate of Incorporation (draft), 1953 (Box-folder 20/1)
    - Preamble to the formation of the National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc., undated (Box-folder 20/2)
    - National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc. By-Laws, 1958 (Box-folder 20/3)
    - National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc. Lists of National Officers, the Board of Governors, Board Members, Chairmen of various committees/committee members, Youth Group Chairmen/Members, undated (Box-folder 20/4)
    - National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc. Rules governing the establishment of Local Executive Boards, undated (Box-folder 20/5)
    - National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc. Constitution and By-Laws for Guilds, undated (Box-folder 20/6)
    - National Negro Opera Foundation. Women's Committee By-Laws, 1959 and undated (Box-folder 20/7)
    - Grant Proposal, 1959 (Box-folder 20/8)
    - Suggested Outline of Organization and Procedures for Helping to Finance and Develop the National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc., July 19, 1960 (Box-folder 20/9)
    - Outline of Plans for Promotion of a Sustaining Fund for the National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc., undated (Box-folder 20/10)
    - Corporate Papers: Miscellaneous papers, 1950-1959 (Box-folder 20/11)
  - Insurance Papers, August 26, 1949 and May 27-28, 1956 (Box-folder 24/4)
  - Memberships and Contributions, 1956-1960, undated (Box 24)
    - Memberships and Contributions. Reiceipts, 1959 and undated (Box-folder 24/5)
    - Memberships and Contributions. Miscellaneous, 1956, 1960 and undated (Box-folder 24/6)
  - Minutes, 1931-1961 (Box 20)
    - Minutes (National Association of Negro Musicians, Inc., Pittsburgh Branch), 1931-1932 (Box-folder 20/12)
    - Minutes (Excutive Board, National Association of Negro Musicians, Inc.), December 27, 1935 (Box-folder 20/13)
    - Minutes (Planning Committee, Washington, D.C. Guild), January-July 1947 (Box-folder 20/14)
    - Minutes (NNOC), June 1948-February 1949 (Box-folder 20/15)
    - Minutes (Washington, D.C. Guild), January-August 1949 (Box-folder 20/16)
    - Minutes (location unknown), July 5, 1949 (Box-folder 20/17)
    - Minutes (Washington, D.C. Guild), May 1949-April 1950 (Box-folder 20/18)
    - Minutes (Board of Directors, NNOC), March-April 1950 (Box-folder 20/19)
    - Minutes (Board of Governors, NNOC), March 28, 1950 (Box-folder 20/20)
    - Minutes (National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc.), April 7, 1953 (Box-folder 20/21)
    - Minutes (Board Meeting, National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc.), February 2, 1954 (Box-folder 20/22)
    - Minutes (Pittsburgh Citizen's Sponsoring Guild, National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc.), September 2, 1954 (Box-folder 20/23)
    - Minutes (New York Guild, NNOC), September 9, 1956 (Box-folder 20/24)
    - Minutes (Special Committee Meeting, National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc.), January 20, 1958 (Box-folder 20/25)
    - Minutes (Committee Meeting), January 27, 1958 (Box-folder 20/26)
    - Minutes (Meeting of Members representing New York, Chicago and Washington Guilds, and other music organizations with Senator J. William Fulbright and W. McNeil Lowry, Director of the Ford Foundation Program in Humanities and the Arts), 1958 (Box-folder 20/27)
    - Minutes (Board of Governors, National Negro Opera Foundation), March 7-June 20, 1959 (Box-folder 20/28)
    - Minutes (Washington Guild), September 17, 1960 (Box-folder 20/29)
    - Minutes (Women's Committee, National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc.), September 24, 1960 (Box-folder 20/30)
    - Minutes (Women's Committee, National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc.), October 1, 1960 (Box-folder 20/31)
    - Minutes (Committee meeting, National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc.), May 27, 1961, Meeting of members of the committee in preparation for the two-day Meet of the National Negro Opera Foundation held on June 3-4, 1961. (Box-folder 20/32)
    - Minutes (Final Conference of the two-day Meet, National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc.), June 4, 1961 (Box-folder 20/33)
  - Miscellany, 1912-1961, undated, Performer lists, lists that have become separated from group photographs, diplomas and certificates belonging to Mary Cardwell Dawson, and other miscellaneous papers. (Box 24, 67)
    - Aida performance. American Guild of Musical Artists, Inc. Delegate lists, April 30, 1949 (Box-folder 24/11)
    - Chicago National Negro Opera Guild. Audition papers, March 29, 1961 (Box-folder 24/11)
    - Costume size lists and forms, undated (Box-folder 24/11)
    - Diploma. Boston. Central Evening High School (Mary L. Cardwell), April 1924 (Box 67)
    - Diploma. Boston. New England Conservatory of Music (Mary Lucinda Cardwell, teacher of the pianoforte course), June 23, 1925 (Box 67)
    - District of Columbia. Municipal Court Judgement, January 23, 1958, Powell-Savory Corporation, t/a New York Amsterdam News [vs.] Mary Cardwell Dawson. (Box-folder 24/11)
    - International Workers Order, Inc. Membership application, February 6, 1945, Photocopy. (Box-folder 24/11)
    - Lease, Town Hall, Inc. Fund-raising concert (April 15, 1945), March 21, 1945 (Box-folder 24/11)
    - License. New York Department of Public Safety, Bureau of Police. Carnegie Hall concert (February 25, 1948), Februrary 20, 1948 (Box-folder 24/11)
    - Nomination lists for Most Outstanding Contribution Award, 1910-1960, circa 1960, Lists of outstanding African-American actors and actresses, composers, conductors, jazz performers, organists, pianists, poets, violinists, and writers that were being considered for this award. (Box-folder 24/7)
    - Permit. Dunbar Vocational High School auditorium. Musical performance (Chicago Negro Opera Guild performance, July 16, 1961), June 14, 1961 (Box-folder 24/11)
    - Photograph identification lists, undated, Lists separated from photographs. (Box-folder 24/11)
    - Public School Certificate. Homestead Grammar Schools (Mary Lucinda Cardwell's graduation certificate), May 27, 1912 (Box-folder 24/11)
    - Speech. Draft, undated (Box-folder 24/11)
    - Subpoena, New York, January 28, 1957, Fragment (page has been torn). (Box-folder 24/11)
  - Notes, 1940s-1961 (Box-folder 23/1-4; 24/10)
  - Ticket Sales, July 11, 1950, August 15, 1952 and undated (Box-folder 24/8)
- Financial Papers, 1936-1962, (55 folders) (Box 25-29)
  Includes budgets and financial reports, bank statements, cancelled checks, withdrawal slips, ticket sales receipts, and various membership and organizational lists.
  Arranged by type of item, and chronologically therein.
  - Budgets and Financial Reports, 1936-1961 (Box 25)
    - Campaign Committee. Financial report, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 25/1)
    - Festival report, 1948 (Box-folder 25/2)
    - Financial report. The Ordering of Moses performance (Shiloh Baptist Church), November 20, 1950 (Box-folder 25/3)
    - Financial report. Faust performance, March 29, 1952 (Box-folder 25/4)
    - Financial report. New York Guild, circa 1956 (Box-folder 25/5)
    - Financial report. Quanga performance, May 27, 1956 (Box-folder 25/6)
    - Financial reports, 1960 (Box-folder 25/7)
    - Financial report. Aida performance, undated (Box-folder 25/8)
    - Financial report. Carmen performance, undated (Box-folder 25/8)
    - Financial reports. Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 25/8)
    - Hamilton National Bank. Statements, 1946-1949 (Box-folder 25/9)
    - Hamilton National Bank. Cancelled checks, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 25/10)
    - Hamilton National Bank. Deposit and withdrawal receipts, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 25/11)
    - Industrial Bank of Washington. Statements, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 25/12)
    - Industrial Bank of Washington. Cancelled checks, 1943-1945, 1959 (Box-folder 25/13)
    - Industrial Bank of Washington. Deposit and withdrawal receipts, 1944-1945, 1949 (Box-folder 25/14)
    - Manufacturers Trust Company. Statements, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 25/15)
    - Manufacturers Trust Company. Cancelled checks, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 25/16)
    - Manufacturers Trust Company. Deposit and withdrawal receipts, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 25/17)
    - Union Trust Company. Statements, 1953, 1957, 1960 (Box-folder 25/18)
    - Union Trust Company. Cancelled checks, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 25/19)
    - Union Trust Company. Deposit and withdrawal receipts, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 25/20)
    - Miscellaneous loan and mortgage papers, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 25/21)
    - Miscellaneous bank paperwork, 1936, 1941, 1947-1948, 1957-1961 (Box-folder 25/22)
  - Ticket Sales Receipts, 1944-1960 (Box 26-27)
    - Ticket sales receipts, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 26/1)
    - Ticket sales receipts, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 26/2)
    - Ticket sales receipts, 1950 (Box-folder 26/3)
    - Ticket sales receipts, 1951 (Box-folder 26/4)
    - Ticket sales receipts, 1952, 1954 (Box-folder 27/1)
    - Ticket sales receipts, 1956 (Box-folder 27/2-3)
    - Ticket sales receipts, 1958 (Box-folder 27/4)
    - Ticket sales receipts, 1959 (Box-folder 27/5)
    - Ticket sales receipts, 1960 (Box-folder 27/6)
    - Ticket sales receipts - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 27/7)
  - Bills and Receipts, Assorted, 1937-1962 (Box 28-29)
    - Bills and receipts, 1937-1942 (Box-folder 28/1)
    - Bills and receipts, 1943 (Box-folder 28/2)
    - Bills and receipts, 1944 (Box-folder 28/3)
    - Bills and receipts, 1945 (Box-folder 28/4)
    - Bills and receipts, 1946 (Box-folder 28/5)
    - Bills and receipts, 1947 (Box-folder 28/6)
    - Bills and receipts, 1948 (Box-folder 28/7)
    - Bills and receipts, 1949 (Box-folder 28/8)
    - Bills and receipts, 1950 (Box-folder 28/9)
    - Bills and receipts, 1951 (Box-folder 28/10)
    - Bills and receipts, 1952 (Box-folder 29/1)
    - Bills and receipts, 1954 (Box-folder 29/2)
    - Bills and receipts, 1955 (Box-folder 29/3)
    - Bills and receipts, 1956 (Box-folder 29/4)
    - Bills and receipts, 1957 (Box-folder 29/5)
    - Bills and receipts, 1958 (Box-folder 29/6)
    - Bills and receipts, 1959 (Box-folder 29/7)
    - Bills and receipts, 1960 (Box-folder 29/8)
    - Bills and receipts, 1961 (Box-folder 29/9)
    - Bills and receipts, 1962 (Box-folder 29/10)
    - Bills and receipts, undated (Box-folder 29/11)
    - Bills and receipts. Fragments, 1940s-1960s (Box-folder 29/12)
- Clippings, 1931-1997, (35 folders) (Box 17-19)
  Newspaper and magazine articles that document the activities of the National Negro Opera Company and related organizations in which Mary Cardwell Dawson was involved. Includes interviews and descriptions of events that honor Dawson and the National Negro Opera Company. Originals and photocopies are included.
  - Clippings, 1931 (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Clippings, 1933 (Box-folder 17/2)
  - Clippings, 1934 (Box-folder 17/3)
  - Clippings, 1935 (Box-folder 17/4)
  - Clippings, 1936 (Box-folder 17/5)
  - Clippings, 1937 (Box-folder 17/6)
  - Clippings, 1938 (Box-folder 17/7)
  - Clippings, 1939 (Box-folder 17/8)
  - Clippings, circa late 1930s (Box-folder 17/9)
  - Clippings, 1940 (Box-folder 17/10)
  - Clippings, 1941 (Box-folder 17/11)
  - Clippings, 1942 (Box-folder 17/12)
  - Clippings, 1943 (Box-folder 18/1)
  - Clippings, 1944 (Box-folder 18/2)
  - Clippings, 1945 (Box-folder 18/3)
  - Clippings, 1946 (Box-folder 18/4)
  - Clippings, 1947 (Box-folder 18/5)
  - Clippings, 1948 (Box-folder 18/6)
  - Clippings, 1949 (Box-folder 18/7)
  - Clippings, circa 1940s (Box-folder 18/8)
  - Clippings, 1950 (Box-folder 18/9)
  - Clippings, 1951 (Box-folder 18/10)
  - Clippings, 1952 (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Clippings, 1953 (Box-folder 19/2)
  - Clippings, 1954 (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Clippings, 1955 (Box-folder 19/4)
  - Clippings, 1956 (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Clippings, 1957 (Box-folder 19/6)
  - Clippings, 1958 (Box-folder 19/7)
  - Clippings, 1959 (Box-folder 19/8)
  - Clippings, 1960 (Box-folder 19/9)
  - Clippings, 1961 (Box-folder 19/10)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 19/11)
  - Clippings, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 19/12)
  - Clippings, undated (Box-folder 19/13)
- Scrapbooks, circa 1940-1961, (3 folders) (Box 65, 68)
  Contains one large scrapbook and several loose pages which were formerly part of a scrapbook.
  - Scrapbook pages, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 65/15)
  - Scrapbook pages, 1954 (Box-folder 65/16)
  - Scrapbook pages, 1940s-1950s (Box-folder 65/17)
  - Scrapbook. National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc., circa 1941-1961 (Box 68)
- Address Lists and Address Books, 1940-1961, (71 folders) (Box 30-35)
  Includes membership lists, committee lists, contact lists, mailing lists, miscellaneous lists, and lists of organizations producing operas in the United States.
  Arranged by type of item.
  - Address Lists, 1940-1961, undated (Box 30-32)
    - Branches of the National Association of Negro Musicians, 1940 (Box-folder 30/1)
    - Carnegie Hall Press list - Main hall, undated (Box-folder 30/2)
    - Members of the National Association of Negro Musicians (local branch), undated (Box-folder 30/3)
    - New York Guild members/Records of fees paid, 1955-1956 and undated (Box-folder 30/4)
    - Records. Campaign minutes and kits, 1949-1953 and undated (Box-folder 30/5)